## Gabriel Lévesque-Duval

273 Emmanuel-Fougerat Laval, QC, H7L 5H5 514-654-4420

<u>glevesqueduval@gmail.com</u>

Languages: French and English

Creative, communicative, and efficient developer determined to help people by creating useful software. Excellent time management by following the agile development frameworks learned during 3 internships and one year of managing a software team of 15 people.

### Skills

- TypeScript, React, React Native
- C#, .NET
- Docker

- Java, Kotlin
- Python
- SQL, GraphQL

# **Experience**

## Software engineering internship

Since May 2023

Expedia Group, Montréal

- Deploy and manage apps in Kubernetes clusters
- Develop high performing Spring Boot applications in Kotlin
- Monitor deployments using Datadog metrics and Splunk logs

### Web and mobile development internship

May 2022 – September 2022

Ora Médical, Montréal

- Develop web applications with React and Next.JS
- Develop mobile applications with React Native
- Data queries with GraphQL and MongoDB

# Full-stack development internship

January 2021 – April 2021

CAE, Montréal

- Develop web application with React, C# and .NET
- Design SQL databases
- Analyse client requirements

#### Web developer

January 2020 – August 2020

Mediavore, Laval

- Back-end web development in PHP
- Maintain web sites of 200 different clients
- Create a bug reporting tool for visual bugs

## **Computer science tutor**

Fall and winter semesters of 2019

Computer science help center of Collège Montmorency, Laval

- Help students in various programming classes
- Supervise students and offer any needed technical assistance

# **Education**

# Bachelor's in software engineering

Since fall 2020

École de technologie supérieure

## **Technical program in computer Science**

2020

Collège Montmorency

### **Student club**

#### Software team leader

Club Capra, Montréal

- Program a mobile robotics platform in Python and C++
- Program a telemetry web user interface using React and Electron
- Task and project management for a team of 15 people
- Competed at Robocup 2022 in Bangkok
- Won the Best in Class Search & Rescue award at EnRicH 2023 in Austria

# **Scholarships**

- 1 000\$ Scholarship of excellence from the Foundation of Collège Montmorency
- Entry scholarship of 2 500\$ at École de technologie supérieure